Carlos Moreno

Curriculum Vitae

Cll. 57 1B - 74 Cali, Colombia *▶* +57 318 606 8507 ⊠ carmoreno.jpg@gmail.com

"What we know is a drop, what we don't know is an ocean." -Isaac Newton

Personal Information

Name Carlos Andrés Moreno Vélez

Nationality Colombian

LinkedIn https://co.linkedin.com/in/carmoreno1

Stack Overflow https://stackoverflow.com/users/4508767/carmoreno

Qwiklabs https://bit.ly/395guA9

Blog https://carmoreno.com.co

Profile

Python Developer

Carlos is a Computer Engineer from Universidad del Valle, he has 4+ years of experience in Software Development with Python Technologies mainly. He has built Apis REST using technologies like Django Rest Framework and CherryPy and desktop solutions with PyQt/PyQt5 together to MySQL, PostgreSQL and Git. He studied around one year in EF English Live academy, where He achieved a C1 (upper-intermediate) English level and He continues to improve his communication skills while using English in his work environment on a daily basis.

He has been exploring Data Science technologies gaining knowledge in Pandas and Numpy studying a Diploma Course at Universidad Nacional de Colombia during 4 months. As like as Cloud technologies using GCP, studying in Qwiklabs. Others technologies which he has knowledge include Lumen, ReactJs, AngularJs Html5 and Css3; and semantic technologies learned at the University in study-groups like RDF and SparQL.

Resourceful, disciplined, restless and always willing to contribute and learn from the work group

Experience

Professional

Dic. 2020 - Current Python Developer Ssr. Advanced, Globant, Cali, Colombia, Data and AI Studio.

- Collaborate on a multi-disciplinary team of developers, testers, data architects, devops in order to create and maintain new reports and data for Education information analysis.
- Manage Gigabytes of sensible data about Students, Teachers, US Districts and Schools.
- Led 2 initiatives: Data Quality and Database Migrations to improve the development experience in the team.
- Coordinate meetings with team members from India and LATAM.

• Language and tools used: Python, Shell, Git, Pandas, Flyway, Airflow, Jupyter Notebook, PostgreSQL, Jira, AWS (Redshift, S3, Datapipeline).

Feb. 2020 - Nov. 2020 Python Developer, Servinformación, Cali, Colombia, Backend Team.

- "Data Rutas Project": Developed new REST endpoints using a framework legacy version (Django Rest Framework v1.4).
- "Servihuella Project": Integrated data from different sources in collaboration with the Secretary of Health and Mayor of Santiago de Cali. Worked with a total of 5 members on the team among Developers, Stakeholders and Managers.
- "Servihuella Project": Automated the cleaning and storing process of daily data related to COVID-19 using Big data technologies.
- \circ Initiated the automated report generations building a desktop application that took 10 Excel files and generated 2 final Excel reports.
- Language and tools used: Python 2.7 and 3+, Django Rest Framework v1.4 (legacy version), CherryPy, Pandas, PyQt, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Git, GCP (Big Query, Cloud SQL, Lambda Functions, App Engine, Cloud Scheduler).

Dec. 2018 - Oct. 2019 Software Engineer, El País Newspaper, Cali, Colombia, Technology Department.

- "Digital Subscriptions Project": Developed new REST Endpoints to integrate with Subscriptions providers like Piano (https://piano.io/). Additionally, participated in the configuration of the rules in the El Pais website (https://www.elpais.com.co) to implement the Digital Subscriptions, this project works for more than 24.000 subscribers daily.
- "Digital Subscriptions Project": Produced a new web application to use as a back-office, in order to sell Digital Subscriptions, it was used by the selling team (three members at that moment).
- "Digital Subscriptions Project": Communicated with differents providers members of Piano to resolve doubts about their product, via email or online conferences. Additionally, communicated with internal Devops members to resolve network errors on the website.
- Language and tools used: Javascript, AngularJS, Git, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, PHP, Lumen.

Dec. 2017 - Nov. 2018 **Django / Angular Developer**, Markaf Colombia, Tuluá, Colombia, Development Team.

- "Markaf App Project": Modeled the internal pay schema of the application: Tables, relations among tables and triggers.
- $\circ\,\,$ "Markaf App Project": Developed new REST endpoint according to stakeholders requests.
- "Markaf App Project": Participated in some frontend tasks, developed Angular visual components according to UI/UX team needs.
- Language and tools used: Python, Django Rest Framework, Javascript, Angular5, Git, PostgreSQL.

Education

Jan. 2021 - Jan. 2022 EF C1 English Level - Advanced, EF English Live.

Aug. 2020 - Dic. 2020 **Diploma in Data Science and Machine Learning**, Universidad Nacional de Colombia.

Feb. 2012 - Jul. 2017 System Engineer, Universidad del Valle.

Awards

Laureate Degree Thesis.

- Carlos got the Laureate Degree for the thesis titled "Creation of Dataset about Ecotourism Information of the Center-Region of Valle del Cauca to publish and link with the Data Web". In this job was applied Semantic Web concepts to model data from different sources and formats, linking these resources with others available on the Web. Finally, the created dataset was used in a web application prototype (Semantic REST) in order to show the information to final users.
- o Language and tools used: RDF, SparQL, Python, AngularJS, Fuseki.

References

Federico López Gómez, Senior Software Engineer, European Bioinformatics Institute | EMBL-EBI, **Contact:** +44 7544 092103.

Mónica María Monsalve, System Engineer, Technology Director, El País Newspaper.

Contact: +57 311 321 8456

MOOCs Courses

- Apache Airflow
- ReactJS Introduction
- RESTFul API using Python and Django Rest Framework

